Matthew Harvey Brandenburgh

3912 Timbalier Dr., Columbus, GA 31907 phone: 706-442-0625 mhbrandenburgh@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

I am a focused person and team player with past years of experience in the filmmaking world, and new to computer programming. Although I worked in videography and independent filmmaking, I also worked as a math and physics tutor, and bring a strong knowledge base and problem-solving skill to my work in technology.

TECH STACK

Javascript, HTML, CSS, Tailwinds, Express.js, Node, SQL, MySQL2, Sequelize, Mongo, Mongoose, Adobe Premiere,

DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Auction Plaza

- An auction website that lets users create an account, list items for sale, and bid on posted items.
- Used node.js, express.js, and SQL, and CSS Tailwinds for design

Workplace Dynamic Scheduler

• A vanilla JavaScript application that accepts user inputs and generates a calendar display of possible employee schedules, using local storage

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tutor, self-employed, September 2005-present

- Aided students from middle school through graduate school primarily in math and physics
- Maintained a 4.9-star rating out of 5 on listing website WyzAnt.com

Freelance Director/Director of Photography/Editor, September 2016-December 2020

- Producing videos for hire under the auspices of my production company, Brandenburgh Media, LLC
- Projects included a music video, numerous commercials and corporate videos for Spectrum Cable in New York

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

Leadership Team, All Souls Young Adults group, June 2010-September 2020

- Produced an ongoing monthly movie night series, choosing titles, leading post-film discussions, and writing essays about the films for attendees to read on their subway rides home
- In addition, planned and led many community events including monthly volunteering projects, book reading groups, concerts, parties, and more

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Physics and Mathematics, University of Georgia, May 2009

Full Stack Flex Coding Bootcamp, Georgia Tech, expected graduation March 2023